Mohamed Khodja

Frontend Engineer

 $medd.khodja@gmail.com \mid linkedin.com/in/medkhodja \mid github.com/mo-jsx \mid \underline{Personal\ Website}$

Passionate software developer with 4 years in frontend development, focused on design systems, performant frontend applications, accessibility, committed top-tier code quality, and exceeding expectations. A deadline-driven problem-solver.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web & Programming: JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, Python Frameworks: Angular, React, React Native, NextJS, ExpressJS, Flask CSS & Preprocess.: CSS, Sass, vanilla-extract, Tailwind, GSAP, Material UI

Testing: Vitest, Jest, Testing-library, Cypress, Selenium, axe

Databases & Storage: MySQL, MongoDB, Prisma, AWS (S3, DynamoDB)

Cloud & Services: AWS (EC2, CloudFront), PlanetScale, Firebase, Sentry, Data Dog, Segment

Tools: Git, GitHub Actions, Turborepo, Docker, Vite, Jira, Spline, Figma

Libraries: Redux, Zustand, RxJS, Loadash, Ramda, Cheerio, Storybook, ThreeJS, D3

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer

June 2021 – Present

Algiers

Pando Tech.

- Worked with cross-functional teams, including managers, designers, backend developers, to deliver Scrum-based features.
- Regularly led meetings to address technical decisions, prioritize tasks, and document the development cycle.
- Facilitated code reviews, pair programming, and mentoring sessions for junior developers to maintain high-quality code.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Led the development of design systems, resulting in } 10\% \ \ \text{reduction in design-related issues and } 20\% \ \ \text{faster development time.}$
- Promoted web accessibility initiatives, following WCAG standards, to ensure inclusive UX and foster a culture of inclusion.
- Applied modern UI/UX principles and optimization techniques, resulting in a 35% increase in user retention over 12 weeks.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Developed GraphQL and REST APIs via Apollo and Express, to deploy on AWS Lambda following industry best practices.}$
- \bullet Implemented proactive monitoring with Data Dog and Sentry, reducing critical errors by 10% and improving response time.
- Utilized GitHub Actions to create and deploy CI/CD pipelines for code on GitHub, which led to 15% faster build time.
- Enhanced code quality via robust testing strategies, achieving 92% code coverage, and reducing bugs by 28% across projects.

Software Engineer - Fullstack

Jan 2023 – July 2023

Taiba Food Company - Ramy

Algiers

- Led frontend development for supply chain platform redesign, applying modern UI/UX principles for an enhanced UX.
- Implemented a map feature for intuitive routing, enhancing the intensive data visualization platform.
- · Collaborated closely with the backend team to integrate frontend components with Flask APIs and endpoints.
- Implemented genetic algorithms, and routing optimization, achieving 20% resource utilization improvement.
- Deployed the backend to an Azure instance ensuring scalability and reliability of the application in the cloud environment.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Performed diverse testing strategies, ensuring high-quality code with } 89\% \ \text{average code coverage using Jest and Cypress.}$

JavaScript Developer - Fullstack

Feb 2019 - Nov 2020

Algiers

- Worked with a dedicated development team of 7 under the agile framework, in a close collaboration with designers.
- Built Chrome Browser Extensions that improved internal teams productivity by 55%.
- \bullet Contributed to B2B e-Commerce projects and developed RESTful APIs using ExpressJS.
- Successfully maintained legacy code, by rewriting 20% of the code base which reduced bugs by 30%.
- Created websites for social media campaigns that led to 35% of users conversion.
- Actively participated in regular planning and brainstorming meetings.

EDUCATION

Bear&Fork

Bachelor in Computer Science

Boumerdes University

Aug 2016 – June 2019

Topics: Algorithmics, Computer architecture, Databases, OOP, Networking, Calculus, Algebra, Probabilities, Physics

PROJECTS

Wojooh Agency - Web application | PHP, Laravel, TypeScript, React, MySQL, Docker

- Built the frontend applications with React, and implemented caching and optimization techniques for a smoother UX.
- Ensured an inclusive UX by following the WCAG standards.

Toothist - Web application | JavaScript, React, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Docker, WebRTC

- Built a full-stack web app with ExpressJS to serve a REST API and React as the frontend, using WebRTC for group calls.
- Implemented OAuth2 for user sign-in, created ChartJS dashboards, and reduced bugs by 35% through Sentry monitoring.

Awards & Extra

- Tqochi e-Commerce, Nominated African Startup of the year, Rabat, Morocco December 2020
- Local Hack Day Algiers March 2018
- HackOn 1st place Algiers Nov.2017

LANGUAGES

English: Advanced | French: Bilingual | Spanish: Conversational | Dutch: Basic | Arabic: Native